





LEANDRO HERNÁN GALEANO

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a strong, skillful, and self-organized Systems Engineer with 15+ years of experience managing various infrastructures and platforms, optimizing the existing environments and connecting with the business needs. Experienced team leader and career coach. Proven experience in automation, scalability, migration to public cloud and DevOps. Microsoft certified. Native Spanish.

SKILLS, PLATFORMS & **TECHNOLOGIES**

- ✓ Proven leadership and contractor management abilities
- ✓ In-depth expertise in troubleshooting Windows Server, with solid understanding Linux servers (mainly Ubuntu and Alpine)
- Hands-on experience with public cloud providers (AWS, Azure) and onpremises to cloud migrations, with MS AZ-900 certification
- ✓ Strong expertise in Azure DevOps way of work: Repositories, Pipelines, Agents, Artifacts and Billing
- ✓ Skilled in virtualization using VMWare and Hyper-V, with a track record of successful physical to virtual migrations
- ✓ Strong scripting abilities in PowerShell, Bash and some Python
- Proficient in container and server-less technologies (Docker, Docker-Compose, Docker Swarm, Kubernetes)
- Experience in server hardware assembly and maintenance
- Networking expertise, including Azure and AWS networking, Cisco ICND1 and experience with wireless solutions from Ubiquiti, Altai, and MikroTik.
- Familiarity with ticket tracking and inventory tools (ServiceNow, Remedy,
- Experience with Microsoft System Center suite (SCOM, SCCM, SCSM, Orchestrator)
- Strong user support skills, both on-site and remote, with helpdesk experience
- Familiarity with ITIL, Six Sigma, HIPAA, GDPR and PCI compliance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

STRONG MIDDLE DEVOPS ENGINEER. INTELLIAS SPAIN.

Dec 2023 – current

Working with a Spanish gambling company that operates gaming machines, casinos, racetracks, and sports betting locations across Latin America, Spain, and Italy. The client also manages online betting platforms and mobile apps with plans to launch a white-label online platform for third-party operators. The client's technology stack required modernization to address outdated, slow, and error-prone processes. I focus on automating and enhancing regular operations, particularly QA automation, while providing recommendations for tool adoption and optimization. The client's online

infrastructure is hosted on Azure's IaaS using Microsoft software stack with QA automation tools including Playwright, SonarQube, Testomat.io, MobSF, and Lighthouse-CI.

Key contributions: Designed, implemented, and maintained Azure DevOps pipelines, reducing CI/CD web frontend cycle time from over a week to half a working day. Provided ad-hoc consultancy on various projects, including PoCs for vendors like Xygeni, Prisma Cloud, Sonatype, and DataDope. Tracked and optimized costs across projects. Advised on best practices for Manual QA and Web development teams, including Git branching strategies and usage of immutable artifacts. Implemented ephemeral testing environments for web developers, enabling faster isolated feature testing with non-production back-end. Developed and deployed an in-house monitoring solution for continuous functional testing using Playwright tests, PowerShell scripting, Uptime-Kuma, and PostgreSQL, improving early detection of service degradation and enhancing end-user experience.

SENIOR SYSTEM ENGINEER - DEVOPS. EPAM SPAIN.

Aug 2022 - Dec 2023

As a DevOps Engineer on one of EPAM's largest customer projects, I played a crucial role in delivering a highly resilient and agile infrastructure to support Development and QA teams. Utilizing a WinOps toolset including Azure DevOps, Azure cloud services, Chef, NuGet, PowerShell, Windows Server, and Docker, I helped improve the customer's infrastructure. Additionally, I worked with cutting-edge security tools like Ilumio and CyberArk to ensure the safety and security of the customer's infrastructure.

CLOUD MIGRATION SPECIALIST, MICROSTRATEGY.

May 2022 – Aug 2022

I assisted customers in modernizing their consumption of MicroStrategy products by migrating from on-premises servers to fully managed cloud platforms on AWS or Azure, tailored to meet each customer's specific needs. My responsibilities included conducting assessments to determine the best approach for each customer, managing network integration, provisioning environments, transforming and loading customer metadata, troubleshooting issues, and ensuring positive user experience. I also collaborated with development teams to address defects and product-specific topics. Upon successful migration to the MicroStrategy Cloud Environment, I transferred support to the lifecycle team.

I also made a personal contribution by reviewing and updating established process documentation and developing a solution to replace third-party paid software (TNTDrive and Cloudberry) with open-source products and custom scripts, allowing for easy and user-friendly access to AWS S3 or Azure blob storage on Windows.

IT CONSULTANT. FREELANCE.

Mar 2020 – Aug 2022

I successfully provided consultation services for the company's transition to Azure cloud, including capacity assessment, documentation, and implementation of the best fitting approach. Through this process, we successfully migrated two core services and a testing/lab environment from physical hardware in a co-location datacenter to Azure

Page | 2 Leandro Hernán Galeano

laaS and PaaS. Additionally, I implemented automation using PowerShell for repetitive server maintenance tasks and managed user access in AD and Office365.

DEVOPS ENGINEER. HEXAWARE.

Nov 2021 – Apr 2022

DevOps Engineer assigned to Ernst & Young, Client Technology Platform project. Provide support for internal teams who require help in moving from old architecture to Cloud Native approach, using in-house developed building blocks, instead of off-the-shelf cloud offerings.

Key contributions: Currently performing an Azure-to-Azure migration, from old self-managed subscription filled with non-standard components, to an IaaC managed infrastructure with internally certified offerings only.

TEAM LEADER. ACCENTURE.

Jul 2019 - Oct 2021

Team lead for Server Engineering and Automation Windows team. Subject matter expert for Intigua Engineering team. Co-developed PowerShell scripts for automated server provisioning, maintenance, security hardening and AWS/Azure tasks.

Key contributions: Expansion and development on Intigua JetAgent usage across new environments in Accenture. Consolidation of a local branch of SE&A – Windows.

IT ARCHITECTURE SENIOR ANALYST. ACCENTURE.

Dec 2016 - Jun 2019

Server Engineering and Automation (SE&A) Windows.

Key contributions: Developed in-house solutions for faster, error-free and more streamlined processes for server deployment and management on a company scale.

IT ARCHITECTURE ANALYST. ACCENTURE.

Jan 2016 - Nov 2016

Server Engineering and Automation team.

Key contributions: streamline of OS template update. Testing 3rd party solutions, some of them were implemented and worked in the process for it. SharePoint infrastructure support.

IT ARCHITECTURE ANALYST. ACCENTURE.

Nov 2014 – Dec 2015

Capacity and Event Management team.

Key contributions: Developed several solutions to achieve the full potential of System Center environment. Took part in several SWAT remediation efforts.

TIER 3 SUPPORT SPECIALIST. GOLDCORP CERRO NEGRO. GOLD MINING COMPANY

Aug 2013 - Mar 2014

Key contributions: Migrated from old local domain to corporate domain. Strengthening the IT infrastructure by implementing some best practices in the industry to fully integrate with corporate network and procedures.

IT ON-SITE SUPPORT SPECIALIST, GOLDCORP CERRO NEGRO

Mar 2013 - Jul 2013

Key contributions: Defined processes for many of the most common tasks. Implemented standard OS images for the computers installed by the department.

WINDOWS SERVER ADMINISTRATOR SSR. ECCO SA. MEDIC COMPANY

Jan 2012 - Feb 2013

Key contributions: Migrated from obsolete hardware and old infrastructure to a new virtualized environment, allowing the company to take advantage of High Availability and clustering. Took part in the physical office move, the datacenter and all the PCs and servers were moved and reinstalled with less than 12 hours of downtime.

IT ON-SITE SUPPORT SPECIALIST. TELETECH ARGENTINA. BPO - CONTACT CENTER.

Oct 2007 - Jun 2011

Honored as Key Player for TeleTech Argentina IT on Nov 2010. Key contributions: Took part in the making of "Hope for Haiti" telethon (2010), we launched a call center operation from scratch in less than a week, coordinating with all IT departments to have everything working for the launch day.

EDUCATION

INSTITUTO SUPERIOR PARTICULAR INCORPORADO № 4011 "GRAL. MANUEL BELGRANO"

System Analyst Degree. 3 credits left to completion.

ESCUELA MEDIA PARTICULAR INCORPORADA Nº 3105 "SANTA TERESITA DEL NIÑO JESÚS".

Humanities and Social Sciences Degree.

REFERENCES

DAVID CORTARELLO

IT Manager – Accenture

(+54 9 341) 5529681 - david.cortarello@accenture.com

SANTIAGO J. VALVANO

IT Superintendent – Goldcorp Cerro Negro

(+1 719) 420 0720 - svalva@hotmail.com

LUCAS M. OLMEDO

TI Infrastructure Coordinator – Ecco SA

(+54 9 341) 6009334 - lukmat@hotmail.com